RAIN LEUNG

▼ rainleung0218@gmail.com 🛗 linkedin.com/in/rain-leung-pystander 🐧 github.com/pystander

Summary

Passionate and interest-driven developer focusing on Software Engineering, Data, and AI/ML. Self-taught generalist across several fields. Active participant of competitive programming contests on 3+ platforms (see GitHub), with 6+ years of programming experience since high school. Fast learner and team player.

Work Experience

Data Engineer Sep 2024 - Present Lalamove Hong Kong

• Developed and maintained backend functionalities (databases, APIs) for several data-related applications, under the guidance of a mentor.

- Configured, built, and released applications based on CI tools and workflows.
- No further details available (signed NDA).

Summer Intern Jun 2023 - Aug 2023

MTR Corporation Limited

Hong Kong

- Built and maintained a new ETL data pipeline from scratch with Python for internal room booking reports, and optimized it with multi-processing to reduce >75\% time overhead.
- Developed web crawlers for 700+ Glassdoor employee reviews and conducted sentiment analysis with NLTK, and presented data in dashboards.
- Migrated and automated old Octopus application process with SharePoint List and Power Automate, from manual inputs to a new semi-auto flow.
- Assisted with UAT, ran test cases, and issued tickets using Redmine.
- Created dashboards and reports for ESG statistics.

Education

The University of Hong Kong Sep 2021 - Jun 2024

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, Second Class Honours (Division One) cGPA 3.32 / 4.3

PolyU Hong Kong Community College

Associate in Engineering, Distinction

Sep 2019 - Jun 2021 cGPA 3.77 / 4.0

Relevant Coursework

- Data Science and Engineering
- Software Engineering
- Data Structures
- Computer Architecture
- Algorithm Design
- Computer Networking
- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning

- Natural Language Processing
- Computer Vision

Technical Skills

Python, Java, C, C++, C#, Kotlin, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, R, Octave Languages

NumPy, Pandas, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, MLflow, BeautifulSoup, Matplotlib, Selenium, Data & AI/ML

SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB

Web Development Flask, FastAPI, Spring, Redis, AWS, Azure, Jekyll

Miscellaneous Linux, Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Unity, Android Studio, Arduino, Redmine, QT, Figma,

Verilog, AutoCAD, SolidWorks

Word-Sea | Python, PyQt5, BeautifulSoup, Software Engineering

Dec 2023

- Developed a vocabulary look-up and jot-down application for English learning.
- Created scripts to crawl, fetch, and parse data from Cambridge Dictionary.
- Designed data structures and models in MVC (Model-View-Controller) architecture.

Simple-ML | Python, ML, NumPy

May 2023

- Implemented Machine Learning algorithms in a simple and minimal way.
- Developed a few classic supervised and unsupervised learning models.

pystander.github.io | HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Jekyll, GitHub Actions

May 2023

- Developed my first personal website as a portfolio.
- Partially based on online boilerplate and hosted statically with Jekyll on GitHub Pages.

Closed-source Projects

Start Date

CP-API | Python, Flask, REST API, Web Scraping, Vercel

Aug 2024

- Built an API for retrieving user info on multiple competitive programming contest platforms.
- Used for the dynamic badges on my GitHub profile (see GitHub).

LLM-Evaluator | Python, NLP, PyTorch, Hugging Face, Prompt Engineering

Mar 2024

- Evaluated public LLMs (e.g., CodeLlama-7b-hf) on coding (HumanEval) and Math reasoning (GSM8K).
- Tested with chain-of-thought (COT), program-of-thought (POT), and retrival-augmented generation (RAG).

NLP-Sentiment-Analysis | Python, NLP, PyTorch, Hugging Face, Keras, Scikit-learn

Feb 2024

- Trained a logistic regression classifier on Rotten Tomatoes (movie reviews).
- Developed statistical LMs (N-gram, TF-IDF, GloVe) as features with >80% accuracy.
- Achieved >90% accuracy with pretrained embedding models (e.g., Instructor).

Dining@HKU | Java, Mobile App Development, Android Studio, Google Maps, School Project

Nov 2023

- Collaborated on a restaurant guide app for HKU campus in a group of 5.
- Built with Google Maps SDKs and APIs for locations and routes.

The-Road-to-Castle-3D | Unity, C#, Game Development, AIGC, School Project

Sep 2023

- Developed a 3D fantasy action RPG as Final Year Project in a 2-man team.
- Implemented an original RPG framework and world editor from scratch with 10,000+ LoC.
- Integrated with AI-generated music and concept arts.

Awards / Achievements

Dean's List Aug 2021

PolyU Hong Kong Community College

Director's List Oct 2020

PolyU Hong Kong Community College

Outstanding Student Award Oct 2020

PolyU Hong Kong Community College